<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<categoryQuestion xmlns="https://www.isaqb.org/ns/exam/foundation/v1" id="Q-20-04-26" points="2">
  <history>
    <item date="2025-02-08">content from mock exam 2024.1-rev0-DE-20240202 and 2024.1-rev0-EN-20240202</item>
  </history>

  <refersToLgs>
    <lg curriculumVersion="2025.1" lg="04-08" />
    <lg curriculumVersion="2023.1" lg="3-8" />
  </refersToLgs>

  <stem>
    <text xml:lang="de">
      Eine Definition lautet: „Softwarearchitektur ist die Summe aller während der Entwicklung gefällten Entscheidungen". Kreuzen Sie an, welche der folgenden Aussagen zu Architektur- /Designentscheidungen richtig und welche falsch sind.
    </text>
    <text xml:lang="en">
      One definition says: "Software architecture is the sum of all the decisions you have taken during development." Check which of the following statements about architectural/design decisions are true and which are false.
    </text>
    <text xml:lang="zh">
      有一种定义是：“软件架构是开发过程中所作出全部决策的总和。”请判断以下关于架构决策/设计决策的陈述哪些正确，哪些错误。
    </text>
  </stem>

  <categoryStatements>
    <categories>
      <category label="a">
        <text xml:lang="de">Richtig</text>
        <text xml:lang="en">true</text>
        <text xml:lang="zh">正确</text>
      </category>
      <category label="b">
        <text xml:lang="de">Falsch</text>
        <text xml:lang="en">false</text>
        <text xml:lang="zh">错误</text>
      </category>
    </categories>
    
    <statements>
      <statement correctCategory="a" identifier="A">
        <text xml:lang="de">Architektonische Entscheidungen können sich in der Struktur der Bausteine oder Komponenten niederschlagen.</text>
        <text xml:lang="en">Architectural decisions can impact the structure of the building block or components.</text>
        <text xml:lang="zh">架构决策可能会影响构建块或组件的结构。</text>
      </statement>
      <statement correctCategory="b" identifier="B">
        <text xml:lang="de">Softwarearchitekt:innen sollten alle Entwurfsentscheidungen schriftlich begründen.</text>
        <text xml:lang="en">Software architects shall justify all design decisions in writing.</text>
        <text xml:lang="zh">软件架构师应该以书面形式说明所有设计决策。</text>
      </statement>
      <statement correctCategory="a" identifier="C">
        <text xml:lang="de">Architektonische Entscheidungen können untereinander Wechselwirkungen haben.</text>
        <text xml:lang="en">Architectural decisions can have interdependencies between each other.</text>
        <text xml:lang="zh">架构决策之间可能存在相互影响。</text>
      </statement>
      <statement correctCategory="a" identifier="D">
        <text xml:lang="de">Kompromisse zwischen zueinander in Konflikt stehenden Qualitätsanforderungen sollten explizite Entscheidungen sein.</text>
        <text xml:lang="en">Tradeoffs between conflicting quality requirements should be explicit decisions.</text>
        <text xml:lang="zh">应明确决定在冲突的质量需求之间进行权衡。</text>
      </statement>
    </statements>
  </categoryStatements>

  <explanation>
    <text xml:lang="de">
      Nicht alle Entscheidungen müssen schriftlich begründet werden - die Anforderung an schriftliche Dokumentation hängt von der Situation, dem Team, dem System und anderen Faktoren ab.
    </text>
    <text xml:lang="en">
      Not all decisions need to be justified in writing - as the requirement for written documentation depends on the situation, the team, the system and other factors.
    </text>
    <text xml:lang="zh">
      并非所有决策都需要以书面形式说明，对书面文档的要求取决于具体情况、团队、系统和其他因素。
    </text>
  </explanation>

</categoryQuestion>
