<pickQuestion id="Q-20-04-07" points="2">
  <history>
    <item date="2024-11-23">content from mock exam 2024.1-rev0-DE-20240202 and 2024.1-rev0-EN-20240202</item>
  </history>

 <refersToLgs>
    <lg curriculumVersion="2025.1" lg="01-03"/>
    <lg curriculumVersion="2025.1" lg="03-02"/>
    <lg curriculumVersion="2025.1" lg="04-01"/>
    <lg curriculumVersion="2023.1" lg="1-4"/>
    <lg curriculumVersion="2023.1" lg="2-2"/>
    <lg curriculumVersion="2023.1" lg="3-1"/>
  </refersToLgs>

  <stem>
    <text xml:lang="de">
      Sie sind als Architekt:in dafür zuständig, ein Altsystem entsprechend den laufenden Betriebsanforderungen am Laufen zu halten. Was sind Ihre DREI wichtigsten Aufgaben?
    </text>
    <text xml:lang="en">
      You are responsible as an architect for keeping a legacy system up and running according to the ongoing requirements of your business. What are the THREE most important action items on your agenda?
    </text>
  </stem>

  <pickOptions>
    <option distractor="distractor" identifier="A">
      <text xml:lang="de">
        Verhandlung des Wartungsbudgets für Ihr Team
      </text>
      <text xml:lang="en">
        Negotiating the maintenance budget for your team
      </text>
    </option>

    <option correct="correct" identifier="B">
      <text xml:lang="de">
        Sicherstellung einer aktuellen Dokumentation des ausgelieferten Systems
      </text>
      <text xml:lang="en">
        Assuring up-to-date documentation of the deployed system
      </text>
    </option>

    <option correct="correct" identifier="C">
      <text xml:lang="de">
        Analyse der Auswirkungen von neuen Anforderungen auf das aktuelle System
      </text>
      <text xml:lang="en">
        Analyzing the impact of new requirements on the current system
      </text>
    </option>

    <option distractor="distractor" identifier="D">
      <text xml:lang="de">
        Ermunterung der Teammitglieder, neue Programmiersprachen zu lernen
      </text>
      <text xml:lang="en">
        Encouraging the team members to learn new programming languages
      </text>
    </option>

    <option correct="correct" identifier="E">
      <text xml:lang="de">
        Ihren Vorgesetzten technologische Updates zusätzlich zu den Geschäftsanforderungen vorschlagen
      </text>
      <text xml:lang="en">
        Suggesting technology updates in addition to the business requirements to your management
      </text>
    </option>
  </pickOptions>

  <explanation>
    <text xml:lang="de">
      Bei der Wartung eines Altsystems sind die wichtigsten Aufgaben einer Architekt:in: 1) Die Dokumentation aktuell zu halten, um das Systemverständnis zu sichern, 2) Die Auswirkungen neuer Anforderungen sorgfältig zu analysieren, um unerwartete Seiteneffekte zu vermeiden, und 3) Proaktiv technologische Aktualisierungen vorzuschlagen, um technische Schulden zu reduzieren und das System zukunftsfähig zu halten. Die Ermutigung zum Lernen neuer Fähigkeiten ist zwar wichtig für die langfristige Entwicklung des Teams, hat aber weniger direkte Priorität für die unmittelbare Wartung des Systems. Budgetverhandlungen sind typischerweise Aufgabe des Projektmanagements.
    </text>
    <text xml:lang="en">
      When maintaining a legacy system, the most important tasks of an architect are: 1) Keeping documentation up-to-date to ensure system understanding, 2) Carefully analyzing the impact of new requirements to avoid unexpected side effects, and 3) Proactively suggesting technological updates to reduce technical debt and keep the system future-proof. While encouraging learning new skills is important for the team's long-term development, it has less immediate priority for system maintenance. Budget negotiations are typically the responsibility of project management.
    </text>
  </explanation>
</pickQuestion>